Standard, William Papers 5258
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
- NWLB. NMU adv. Army Transport Service, 1943-1944 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  Contains pamphlet Opportunities in the United States Merchant Marine. Oversize exhibit materials separated and house in flat files (box10).
- NWLB. NMU adv. Army Transport Service, 1943-1944 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  Contains pamphlet Opportunities in the United States Merchant Marine.
- NWLB. NMU adv. Atlantic Gulf and Steamship Company, 1945 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  Contains newspaper clippings.
- NWLB. NMU adv. Atlantic Gulf and Steamship Company, 1945 (Box 3, Folder 11)
- NWLB. NMU adv. Atlantic Gulf and Steamship Company, 1945 (Box 3, Folder 12)
- NWLB. NMU adv. Atlantic Gulf and Steamship Company, 1945 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  Contains newspaper clippings and pamphlet "Substandard Wages," by the Textile Workers Union of America.
- NWLB. NMU adv. Cities Service Oil Company, 1945 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  Correspondence with U.S. Conciliation Service.
- NWLB. NMU adv. Ford Motor Company, 1942-1945 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  Contains Ford Agreement.
- NWLB. NMU adv. Ford Motor Company, 1942-1945 (Box 3, Folder 16)
- National War Labor Board. Transcript., 1945 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  NMU adv. Atlantic Gulf and Steamship Company, pp. 1-332.
- NWLB. NMU adv. Pittsburgh Supply, 1943-1945 (Box 3, Folder 18)
- NWLB. NMU adv. Standard Fruit and Steamship Company, 1943-1945 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  Includes verbatim transcript of May 14, 1944 hearing before the Board
- NWLB. NMU adv. Standard Fruit and Steamship Company, 1943-1945 (Box 3, Folder 20)
- NWLB. NMU adv. Standard Fruit and Steamship Company, 1943-1945 (Box 3, Folder 21)
- Broadsides in support of Merchant Seamen, 1942-1945 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  For letter writing campaign to NWLB in support of raising seamen's wages.
- NLRB. Agwilines. Purser Election., 1947 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- NLRB. American Trading and Production Corp., 1942-1946 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- NLRB. Benson, Albert vs. Boland and Cornelius, 1947 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  Petition in re allowing NMU onto ballot.
- NLRB. Bethlehem Transportation Company. Correspondence., 1944-1946 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  In re overtime wages.
- NLRB. Bethlehem Transportation Company. Case notes and filings., 1941-1946 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  In re overtime wages. File contains Agreement between NMU and Great Lakes' Tanker Companies, 1941.
- NLRB. Bethlehem Transportation Company. Agreement and consent election., 1944-1946 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- NLRB. Brown Steamship Company., 1944-1948 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- NLRB. Cities Service Oil Company. Ballot cards and correspondence., 1946-1947 (Box 4, Folder 8)
- NLRB. Cities Service Oil Company. Unfair labor charge., 1946-1947 (Box 4, Folder 9)
- NLRB. Cities Service Oil Company. Affidavit on collusion., 1946-1947 (Box 4, Folder 10)
- NLRB. Cities Service Oil Company. Violation of Wagner Act., 1946-1947 (Box 4, Folder 11)
- NLRB. Cities Service Oil Company. Unlawful labor practices., 1946-1947 (Box 4, Folder 12)
- NLRB. Cities Service Oil Company. Report from NMU organizer., 1946-1947 (Box 4, Folder 13)
- NLRB. Cleveland Cliffs Iron Company., 1944-1945 (Box 4, Folder 14)
- NLRB. General Petroleum Corp. of California., 1942 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  Includes pamphlet "Pursers Sum it Up! It's NMU for You!"
- NLRB. Grace Lines., 1946-1947 (Box 4, Folder 16)
- NLRB. Great Lakes Conference., 1947 (Box 4, Folder 17)
- NLRB. Hanna Company., 1946-1948 (Box 4, Folder 18)
- NLRB. Honest Ballot Association., 1938-1946 (Box 4, Folder 19)
- NLRB. Isthmian Steamship Company., 1944-1947 (Box 4, Folder 20)
- NLRB. Maritime Elections., 1942-1944 (Box 4, Folder 21)
- NLRB. Mathiason Tanker Corporation., 1946-1947 (Box 4, Folder 22)
- NLRB. Marine Engineers Beneficial Association (MEBA), 1942-1946 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  Includes 1942 and 1943 constitutions, proceedings of the 1945 convention, several broadsides and a membership list of Local No. 1.
- NLRB. Marine Engineers Beneficial Association (MEBA), 1942-1946 (Box 4, Folder 24)
- NLRB. Marine Engineers Beneficial Association (MEBA), 1942-1946 (Box 4, Folder 25)
- NLRB. Marine Engineers Beneficial Association (MEBA), 1942-1946 (Box 4, Folder 26)
- NLRB. Marine Engineers Beneficial Association (MEBA), 1942-1946 (Box 4, Folder 27)
- NLRB. Midland Steamship Company., 1943-1947 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  Includes handwritten research notes.
- NLRB. Midland Steamship Company., 1943-1947 (Box 4, Folder 29)
- NLRB. Newtex Steamship Corp., 1947-1948 (Box 4, Folder 30)
- NLRB. Nicholson Steamship Company, 1943 (Box 4, Folder 31)
- NLRB. Pittsburgh Pamphlet, 1946 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  Includes correspondence and a typescript of a pamphlet regarding Pittsburgh Steamship Company vs. NMU trial report by the NLRB.
- NLRB. Ponchelet Marine Steamship Company, 1946-1947 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  Contains collective bargaining petitions with signatures.
- NLRB. Pursers., 1945-1946 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  Contains pamphlet "Pursers Sum it Up! It's NMU for You!" and broadsides.
- NLRB. Richfield Steamship Company., 1942 (Box 5, Folder 1)
- NLRB. Standard Oil Company., 1942-1945 (Box 5, Folder 2)
- NLRB. Sun Oil Company, 1946-1947 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  Includes completed membership application cards, membership list and several pages of handwritten notes.
- NLRB. Texas Company, 1943-1948 (Box 5, Folder 4)
- NLRB. War Emergency Tankers, 1945-1946 (Box 5, Folder 5)
- War Shipping Administration. Amorin, Joseph, 1943 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  War risk insurance claim. He was on a merchant ship that was torpedoed in Black Sea and wounded.
- War Shipping Administration. Recruitment and Manning Organization, 1942-1945 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  Includes excerpt from Federal Register dated March 20, 1943.
- War Shipping Administration. Steinberg, Ethel., 1942 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  Widow trying to collect insurance after death of her husband.
- War Shipping Administration. Allocation of Ships., 1941-1944 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  Proposed agreements and policies.
- War Shipping Administration. Allocation of Ships., 1941-1944 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  Service agreement.
- War Shipping Administration. Allocation of Ships., 1941-1944 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  Agreement with appendices.
- War Shipping Administration. Allocation of Ships., 1941-1944 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  Final Agreement and bulletin to NMU members.
- War Shipping Administration. Allocation of Ships., 1941-1944 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  Correspondence file.
- War Shipping Administration. Allocation of Ships., 1941-1944 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  Newspaper clippings, research notes, drafts of agreement, and lists of ships.
- Car Ferries. Presidential Emergency Board. Transcript, 1948 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  NMU adv. Pere Marquette (C&O), Ann Arbor Railroad, Grand Trunk Western Railway, and Wabash Railroad.
- Car Ferries. Presidential Emergency Board. Transcript, 1948 (Box 5, Folder 16)
- Car Ferries. Presidential Emergency Board. Transcript, 1948 (Box 5, Folder 17)
- Aliens-Deportation to U.S. Allies, 1942-1943 (Box 5, Folder 18)
- Allied Powers (Maritime Courts) Act, 1941 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  Contains The Inter Allied Review magazine.
- Anti-Labor Laws, State level, 1947-1948 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  CIO bulletins.
- Anti-Labor Laws, Delaware, 1947 (Box 5, Folder 21)
- Anti-Labor Legislation, 1947 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  Opposing testimony delivered to the Senate Committee on Labor by Phillip Murray (president, CIO)
- Anti-Labor Legislation, 1947 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  Opposing testimony and submissions to the Senate Committee on Labor.
- Anti-Poll Tax Legislation, 1942-1945 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  Lobbying efforts by the CIO and the NMU.
- Anti-Poll Tax Legislation, 1942-1945 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  Clippings file. Includes pamphlets "NMU Fights Jim Crow" and "Voting Restrictions in the 13 Southern States."
- CIO Maritime Committee, 1947 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  Reports on CIO lobbying against anti-Union legislation
- Memoranda on anti-Labor Legislation, 1947 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  Address by Senator James E. Murray
- Civil Aviation and Civil Aeronautics Bills, 1943 (Box 5, Folder 28)
- Omnibus Bill HR 133 and SR 62. War Shipping Administration., 1943 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  To provide benefits to members of the Merchant Marine who serve(d) during the war equivalent to those received by members of the armed forces.
- Benefits for Seamen, Omnibus Bill. Correspondence., 1942-1943 (Box 5, Folder 30)
- Benefits for Seamen-Omnibus Bill. CIO Maritime Committee Reports., 1942-1943 (Box 5, Folder 31)
- Benefits for Seamen-Omnibus Bill. Statement submitted by William Standard., 1942-1943 (Box 5, Folder 32)
  Includes broadside.
- HR 6292: Certificates of Service to applicants for engine room ratings, 1941-1942 (Box 5, Folder 33)
- Civilian War Benefits Act of 1942 (Box 5, Folder 34)
- Disability-Seamen's Disability Insurance (Public Law 17), 1943-1948 (Box 5, Folder 35)
- Disability-Seamen's Disability Insurance (Public Law 17), 1943-1948 (Box 5, Folder 36)
- Education-Servicemen's Education and Training Act of 1944, 1943-1944 (Box 6, Folder 1)
- Education-War Service Education and Training Act, 1943-1944 (Box 6, Folder 2)
- Employees of the U.S, Its Territories or Possessions, 1941-1943 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  Guaranteed a return to previous employment following service in the Merchant Marine and includes similar legislation introduced in New York State.
- Labor Disputes-War Labor Disputes Act (Smith/ Connelly), 1943-1945 (Box 6, Folder 4)
- Labor Fact Finding Boards, 1946-1947 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  In re Case Bill (Anti-Union legislation) and NLRB.
- Labor Fact Finding Boards, 1946-1947 (Box 6, Folder 6)
- Life Insurance, 1943 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  Amendment to the National Life Insurance Act of 1940 in order to make insurance available to Merchant Marines.
- Lobbying, Federal Regulation of, 1946-1947 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  Includes various statement and report forms required to be filed by lobbyists with the clerk of the House.
- Lobbying, Federal Regulation of, 1946-1947 (Box 6, Folder 9)
- Logging of Seamen, 1942-1943 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  Giving funds to dependents of merchant marines killed in action.
- Manford Act (Texas State Law), 1948 (Box 6, Folder 11)
- Merchant Seamen's War Service Act, 1944-1946 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  Includes broadsides and handwritten notes. Referred to as "Seamen's Bill of Rights."
- Merchant Seamen's War Service Act, 1944-1946 (Box 6, Folder 13)
- Merchant Seamen's War Service Act, 1944-1946 (Box 6, Folder 14)
- Merchant Ship Sales Act, 1944-1945 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  Sale of government owned merchant vessels.
- Movement of property and information into and out of the U.S. and movement of persons out of the U.S., 1942 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  Suspension of tariff and immigration law for the duration of the war.
- Muster Out Pay Bill, 1944 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  For merchant marines.
- Naturalization of Merchant Seamen during the War, 1943-1944 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  For the naturalization of seamen who serve on an American vessel for at least three years.
- Extension of Navy Court Martial Jurisdiction During the War, 1942 (Box 6, Folder 19)
- Public Health Service Code, 1943-1944 (Box 6, Folder 20)
- Public Health Service Code, Proposed Amendment to, 1943-1944 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  Written by William Standard.
- Public Vessels Act of 1925 (amended), 1943-1944 (Box 6, Folder 22)
- Red Sea Charters repayment to Treasury of $28 million in excessive profits, 1943 (Box 6, Folder 23)
- Relief fund for seamen made available to dependents of deceased seamen, 1942 (Box 6, Folder 24)
- Sabotage/Espionage protection of war industries and the Merchant Marines, 1943 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  Letter from NMU condemning bill because of its targeting of immigrants and foreign national merchant seamen.
- Sabotage-New York State legislation proposed to prevent sabotage, 1942 (Box 6, Folder 26)
- Safety at Sea Investigation, 1942-1945 (Box 6, Folder 27)
  Affidavits from merchant seamen, who were on boats that were attacked and/or sank, describing lack of safety features on the cargo ships.
- Safety at Sea Investigation, 1942-1945 (Box 6, Folder 28)
  Reports on sinkings, firing on torpedoes sailors in the water, request for war crimes commission, and reports from ships carrying Lend-Lease cargo. Includes newspaper clippings, magazine article and pamphlet Who's Guilty?
- Security (Post War) for Merchant Marines and the armed forces, 1943 (Box 6, Folder 29)
- Ship Construction Reserve Fund, 1943-1944 (Box 6, Folder 30)
- Ship Construction Reserve Fund-Tax Exemption, 1941-1943 (Box 6, Folder 31)
- Staff Officers Bill, 1939 (Box 6, Folder 32)
- Statute revision suspending the 50% duty on equipment purchase or ship repair in a foreign city, 1943 (Box 6, Folder 33)
- Stowaways on Vessels, 1943 (Box 6, Folder 34)
- Social Security Bill (Murray-Wagner-Dingell Bill), 1943-1944 (Box 6, Folder 35)
  Includes reprints from the Lawyers Guild Review V. III, No.
- Social Security Bill (Murray-Wagner-Dingell Bill), 1943-1944 (Box 6, Folder 36)
- Special Committee to Investigate Conditions in the Merchant Marine, Hearings, 1939 (Box 6, Folder 37)
- Suspending Operating-Differential Subsidy Agreements During the War, 1943 (Box 6, Folder 38)
- Taft-Hartley Bill, 1947 (Box 6, Folder 39)
  Includes newspaper clippings.
- Taft-Hartley Bill, 1947 (Box 6, Folder 40)
  Includes analysis by National Lawyers' Guild.
- Taft-Hartley Bill, 1947 (Box 6, Folder 41)
  Includes CIO pamphlet "The Drive Against Labor."
- Training of Merchant Marine personnel, 1943 (Box 6, Folder 42)
- U.S. Arbitration Act, 1942 (Box 6, Folder 43)
- Vocational Rehabilitation Act Amendments, 1943 (Box 6, Folder 44)
- Voting in Federal Elections by Merchant Seamen, 1942 (Box 6, Folder 45)
- Voting. Soldier's Vote Bill, 1943-1944 (Box 6, Folder 46)
- War Contract Renegotiation, 1943-1944 (Box 6, Folder 47)
- War Shipping Field Service, Creation of, 1943 (Box 6, Folder 48)
- NMU's Position on Misc. Legislation, 1943 (Box 6, Folder 49)
  In re HR 664, 684, and 498
- 78th Congress Legislation, 1943-1944 (Box 6, Folder 50)
- 80th Congress Legislation, 1947 (Box 6, Folder 51)
- General NMU. American Merchant Marine Institute, question re insurance for representatives, 1942-1943 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  Includes two boarding passes and agreement.
- General NMU. Bonus Dispute, 1942-1946 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  For merchant seamen injured in the line of duty
- General NMU. Brown, et al. vs. Atlantic Coast Lines, 1942-1943 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  ICC proceedings regarding discrimination against African- American merchant seamen. Includes article by W. Standard, "Maritime Workers and the War: Railroad Discrimination Against Negro Seamen." Also includes Standard's research, case notes, and drafts of
- General NMU. Brown, et al. vs. Atlantic Coast Lines, 1942-1943 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  ICC filings including affidavits and brief. Also newspaper clipping from NY Post "ICC Upholds Jim Crow."
- General NMU. Brown, et al. vs. Atlantic Coast Lines, 1942-1943 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  ICC filing of complaint.
- General NMU. Brown, et al. vs. Atlantic Coast Lines, 1942-1943 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  ICC filing of reply.
- General NMU. Brown, et al. vs. Atlantic Coast Lines, 1942-1943 (Box 7, Folder 7)
- General NMU. Brown, et al. vs. Atlantic Coast Lines, 1942-1943 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  ICC filing of Exceptions and supporting points.
- General NMU. Brown, et al. vs. Atlantic Coast Lines, 1942-1943 (Box 7, Folder 9)
- General NMU. Brown, et al. vs. Atlantic Coast Lines, 1942-1943 (Box 7, Folder 10)
- General NMU. Brown, et al. vs. Atlantic Coast Lines, 1942-1943 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  Correspondence, draft of Standard's article on discrimination for The Pilot (NMU newspaper), decision by ICC to support Jim Crow segregation, NY Post article "Big Railroads Accused of Encouraging Race Bias," and depositions of Clarence Brown and Thomas Jo
- General NMU. Camp Kittiwake Merchant Marine Rest Center, 1944 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  Facility located in Pass Christian, Mississippi. The town passed Jim Crow segregation ordinances to prohibit African-American merchant seamen from being treated there. The NMU appealed to the War Shipping Administration to stop the ordinance; it declined
- General NMU. Collateral Issues (Fly Arbitration Award) [Folder 1 of 11], 1946-1947 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  Includes newspaper clippings, statements, financial statement, numerous exhibits and press releases
- General NMU. Collateral Issues (Fly Arbitration Award) [Folder 2 of 11], 1946-1947 (Box 7, Folder 14)
- General NMU. Collateral Issues (Fly Arbitration Award) [Folder 3 of 11], 1946-1947 (Box 7, Folder 15)
- General NMU. Collateral Issues (Fly Arbitration Award) [Folder 4 of 11], 1946-1947 (Box 7, Folder 16)
- General NMU. Collateral Issues (Fly Arbitration Award) [Folder 5 of 11], 1946-1947 (Box 7, Folder 17)
- General NMU. Collateral Issues (Fly Arbitration Award) [Folder 6 of 11], 1946-1947 (Box 7, Folder 18)
- General NMU. Collateral Issues (Fly Arbitration Award) [Folder 7 of 11], 1946-1947 (Box 7, Folder 19)
- General NMU. Collateral Issues (Fly Arbitration Award) [Folder 8 of 11], 1946-1947 (Box 7, Folder 20)
- General NMU. Collateral Issues (Fly Arbitration Award) [Folder 9 of 11], 1946-1947 (Box 7, Folder 21)
- General NMU. Collateral Issues (Fly Arbitration Award) [Folder 10 of 11], 1946-1947 (Box 7, Folder 22)
- General NMU. Collateral Issues (Fly Arbitration Award) [Folder 11 of 11], 1946-1947 (Box 7, Folder 23)
- General NMU. United States adv. Couchoir, Daniel, 1943 (Box 7, Folder 24)
  Sedition trial for former NMU member; not represented by NMU. Includes newspaper clipping
- General file. Daily Peoples World, vol. 6, no. 43., 1943 (Box 7, Folder 25)
  February 20, 1943.
- General NMU. Louisiana Act 106, 1943 (Box 7, Folder 26)
  Discrimination. Segregated housing in Louisiana
- General NMU. Elections of 1944, Union and National., 1943-1944 (Box 7, Folder 27)
  Includes broadsides and pamphlets "It's Your Union" in re NMU elections. Also includes pamphlet "People's Rights and the 1944 Elections: A comparative record of Franklin D. Roosevelt vs. Thomas E. Dewey."
- General NMU. Election of 1945, 1943-1944 (Box 7, Folder 28)
  Includes broadsides and a sample ballot for the NMU elections.
- General NMU. Emblem Registration, 1942-1944 (Box 7, Folder 29)
  Includes patent application with schematic drawings of three pins, two honoring NMU veterans of foreign wars and one celebrating merchant marines, and correspondence with the Library of Congress in re trademarking the NMU emblems.
- General NMU. Emblem Registration, 1942-1944 (Box 7, Folder 30)
  Includes booklet "General Information Concerning Patents" and a magazine "The American Pilot" that the NMU felt was infringing upon their copyright.
- General NMU. Report of William Standard on the Status of Claims Against the NMU for Funeral and Death Benefits, 1939-1941 (Box 7, Folder 31)
  List of 43 NMU members who's dependents filed claims.
- General NMU. Grimes vs. Merrill Stevens Dry Dock (Closed Shop), 1947 (Box 7, Folder 32)
  Includes motions, statements, and bills of complaint.
- General NMU. High vs. NMU, 1940 (Box 7, Folder 33)
  In re petty suit against The Pilot (NMU's newsletter)
- General NMU. Immigration, Expediting the naturalization of alien seamen, 1943-1946 (Box 7, Folder 34)
  Includes pamphlet "The Challenge of Our Immigration Laws" by the American Committee for the Protection of Foreign Born, a guide for port agents that lists acceptable immigration quotas.
- General NMU. Immigration, Silva Case, 1942 (Box 7, Folder 35)
  Case of merchant seaman who was born in Portugal, but who lived in the U.S. from 9 months of age.
- General NMU. Li, Hin vs. U.S. Navigation, 1944 (Box 7, Folder 36)
  Includes witness statements and a copy of the legal retainer.
- Liquor, Food and Entertainment License for Union Hall, 1944-1945 (Box 7, Folder 37)
- General NMU. Ludor, Otto vs. American Foreign Steamship Company, 1943 (Box 7, Folder 38)
  Recovery of owed wages
- General NMU. Mrs. Maskey, 1942 (Box 7, Folder 39)
  Correspondence from widow of merchant seaman
- General NMU. Merchant Marine Council, 1942 (Box 7, Folder 40)
  Contains meeting minutes
- General NMU. Metts, James, 1943-1944 (Box 7, Folder 41)
  Arrested by Coast Guard for 'seditious acts,' cleared of all charges.
- General NMU. National Maritime Day, 1943-1946 (Box 7, Folder 42)
  Includes broadsides and programs celebrating National Maritime Day.
- General NMU. National Maritime Day, 1943-1946 (Box 7, Folder 43)
  Includes Wood Ad Mats (relief images) and broadside which uses Wood Ad Mats to print images. Also includes program for celebration, press releases, and invitations to the opening of the NMU War Memorial.
- General NMU. National Seamen's Anchor Club, 1944 (Box 7, Folder 44)
  Checking to see if this is a social club or something else.
- General file. Council on African Affairs, 1942-1945 (Box 7, Folder 45)
  Includes pamphlet "What of Africa's Place in Tomorrow's World?" and several issues of the monthly bulletin New Africa. Includes signed, personal correspondence from Paul Robeson.
- General NMU. Jose Pastor y Martin, application for citizenship, 1942 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  Merchant seaman who violated Volstead Act (Prohibition) and had to prove he served his sentence.
- General NMU. Pension Fund, 1943 (Box 8, Folder 2)
- General NMU. The Pilot, 1944-1948 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  Includes issue of 5/16/47
- General NMU. The Pilot, 1944-1948 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  Includes issue of 5/16/48
- General NMU. CIO Political Action Committee, 1944-1947 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  Correspondence
- General NMU. Port Committee, 1944 (Box 8, Folder 6)
- General NMU. Raskin, Joseph, 1943 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  Obtain visa fro Raskin's wife
- General NMU. Real Estate Holdings of NMU, 1943 (Box 8, Folder 8)
- General NMU. Reorganization of NMU, 1939 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  Includes the guide "An Outline - With Methods of Work for all Officials, Agents, Organizers and Patrolmen of the National Maritime Union."
- General NMU. Resolutions (Box 8, Folder 10)
- General NMU. Riviera vs. U.S. Linea (Workplace injury), 1942 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  Includes handwritten notes
- General NMU. Rose, Joseph (New Orleans Agent), 1944-1946 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  NMU Trial, includes copy of indictment (for theft).
- General NMU. S.S. Lake Traverse, Discrimination, 1942-1943 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  Investigation into workplace discrimination again seamen of color.
- General NMU. New York City Sales Tax, 1942 (Box 8, Folder 14)
- General NMU. Sleepy Lagoon Defense Committee, discrimination again Mexican-Americans., 1943-1944 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  Includes briefs, magazine Sleepy Lagoon Mystery, broadsides, petitions, newsletter, booklet The Sleepy Lagoon Case. William Standard filed an Amicus Brief in the successful Appellate proceedings. The case involved 17 young men of Mexican descent being wro
- General NMU. Sleepy Lagoon Defense Committee, 1943-1944 (Box 8, Folder 16)
- General NMU. Social Security, 1942 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  Includes booklets How to Calculate Benefits Under Federal Old Age and Survivors Insurance and Old Age and Survivors Insurance for Workers and their Families
- General NMU. Subsidies Studies (Box 8, Folder 18)
  For merchant marines in post-war America.
- General files. Taxation Material, 1941-1943 (Box 8, Folder 19)
  Includes booklets Inflation: What Can We Do About It?; A Democratic Tax Program for America at War; An Equitable Pay-As-You-Go Tax Plan; and copies of the newsletter The Guild Lawyer dated April and September 1942
- General NMU. United Seamen's Services, 1942-1947 (Box 8, Folder 20)
  Includes booklet Men Against Torpedoes, articles of incorporation, and handwritten notes
- General NMU. United Seamen's Services, 1942-1947 (Box 8, Folder 21)
- General NMU. Washington Newsletter, Issued by the CIO Maritime Committee, 1947 (Box 8, Folder 22)
  January 1947 - May 1947